For this question you're asked to decide which of the procedures run in linear time.
对于这个问题 你要确定哪些过程 以线性时间运行
That is, the running time scales linearly with the length of the input.
也就是说 运行时间与输入长度成线性增加
What we need to make sure is that there aren't too many steps.
我们需要确定没有太多的步骤
If we have a look at the first procedure,
如果我们看看第一个过程
we initialize a variable--that doesn't take very much time.
我们初始化一个变量 不会花费很多时间
Then we have a for loop, and the for loop iterates through the input list here.
然后我们有 for 循环 迭代这个输入列表
If nothing happens in here, then it will iterate input list times.
如果这里没发生任何事 它迭代"输入列表长度"次数
In order for it to be linear, the steps within the for loop must be in constant time.
要成为线性 for 循环的步骤 必须花费固定时间
What are we doing?
我们在这里做什么？
We're just comparing the variable maximum with an element,
我们正在比较变量 maximum 与 element
and then if the comparison is true, then we're setting maximum to be the element.
如果比较结果为 True 我们要设定 maximum 为 element
This is just looking for the maximum element in the list.
这在寻找列表中的最大元素
That's just a constant time operation there.
这只是固定时间的操作
So that is constant time, so procedure 1 does run in linear time.
这就是固定时间 所以过程 1 的确以线性时间来执行
Now onto our second procedure. What's it doing?
现在到第二个过程 它在做什么？
It's taking the first element of the input list and adding it onto sum.
它采用输入列表中的第一个元素 把它加入 sum
Sum starts at zero and then adds the first element of the input list,
sum 从零开始 然后加上输入列表的第一个元素
and then the input list is set to be the second element onwards in the list.
然后输入列表设为 从列表的第二个元素起的列表
Then it keeps summing. Now, how many steps does this take?
然后它不断地叠加 现在 这花了多少步骤？
Well, it just cuts off the first element each time in the list.
嗯 它每次只是删掉列表中的第一个元素
That's the one that we've already added on.
也就是我们已经加入 sum 的元素
Then the list continues as long as it's not empty.
然后只要列表不是空的 就继续下去
This is actually performed the length of the input list times.
这实际上执行了"输入列表长度"次数
One thing we always need to look at when we're doing this
我们做评估时 总是需要看的一件事是
is to check whether they're constant time.
检查他们是否是固定时间
You're told in the question that both of these are constant time,
问题已告诉你 这两个是固定时间
which means that the whole procedure runs in linear time.
这意味着 整个过程以线性时间运行
Now onto procedure 3.
现在到过程 3
What it's doing is running through the list, checking each element against every other element.
它正逐一执行列表 检查每个元素与其它的每个元素
If you're not checking at element against itself and the two elements are the same,
如果你不是在对比该元素与它自身 而且这两个检查对象是相同的元素
then return false.
传回 False
Otherwise, return true.
否则 传回 True
It's checking whether there is a repeated element in the list.
它检查列表中是否有重复的元素
Now, looking at how it's done it, this inner loop here runs through all the values of j.
现在看看它是如何做的 这个内部循环遍历了所有 j 值
In the worst case, when the input list of i is never equal to the input list j--
最糟的情况是 当 i 的输入列表永远不等于输入列表 j 时
when i and j are different--this will run through the whole list.
当 i 和 j 不同时 这会执行整个列表
This is going to go through length of input list times in the worst case.
最糟的情况下 这会执行 '输入列表长度' 次数
The inner loop for j--that's going to go through that many times.
内部循环的 j 通过 '输入列表长度' 次数
Now, it's going to go through that many times when i = 0 and when i = 1 and when i = 2 and so on.
现在 它要经过很多次 当 i = 0  i = 1  i = 2等等
It's actually going to go through that inner loop length of input times.
它实际上要经过内部循环 '输入列表长度' 次数
That's squared and if it's something squared, it's no longer linear.
这是平方 如果某件事是平方 就不是线性的
So this is not linear time.
所以这不是线性时间
The correct answer was procedures 1 and 2 run in linear with respect to the input list,
正确答案是对于输入列表 过程 1 和 2 以线性时间运行
and procedure 3 does not.
过程 3 则不是